<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on Inria/Irisa DiverSE Team</title><link>http://example.org/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on Inria/Irisa DiverSE Team</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chaos Engineering for IoT and Network Services</title><link>http://example.org/projects/chaos-engineering-for-iot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/chaos-engineering-for-iot/</guid><description>The main objective of the PhD is to integrate chaos engineering principles to IoT Service frameworks. This integration shall improve the robustness of software-defined network services, shall also help to explore the concept of equivalence for software-defined network services and help to build an approach to constantly evolve the attack surface of network services.</description></item><item><title>Faber Novel PhD grant</title><link>http://example.org/projects/fabernovel-phd-grant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/fabernovel-phd-grant/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Gemoc Initiative</title><link>http://example.org/projects/gemoc-initiative/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/gemoc-initiative/</guid><description>The GEMOC initiative is an open and international initiative launched in 2013 that coordinate research partners worldwide to develop breakthrough software language engineering (SLE) approaches that support global software engineering through the use of multiple domain-specific languages. GEMOC members aim to provide effective SLE solutions to problems associated with the design and implementation of collaborative, interoperable and composable modeling languages. The GEMOC initiative aims to provide a framework that facilitates collaborative work on the challenges of using of multiple domain-specific languages in software development projects.</description></item><item><title>GLOSE INRIA/SAFRAN Labs</title><link>http://example.org/projects/glose-inria-safran/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/glose-inria-safran/</guid><description>The GLOSE project develops new techniques for heterogeneous modeling and simulation in the context of systems engineering. It aims to provide formal and operational tools and methods to formalize the behavioral semantics of the various modeling languages used at system-level. These semantics will be used to extract behavioral language interfaces supporting the definition of coordination patterns. These patterns, in turn, can systematically be used to drive the coordination of any model conforming to these languages.</description></item><item><title>H2020 STAMP EU Project</title><link>http://example.org/projects/stamp/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/stamp/</guid><description>STAMP stands for Software Testing AMPlification. Leveraging advanced research in automatic test generation, STAMP aims at pushing automation in DevOps one step further through innovative methods of test amplification. December 1, 2016 - November 31, 2019</description></item><item><title>ICT COST Action MPM4CPS (IC1404)</title><link>http://example.org/projects/mpm4cps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/mpm4cps/</guid><description>Truly complex, designed systems, known as Cyber Physical Systems (CPS), are emerging that integrate physical, software, and network aspects. To date, no unifying theory nor systematic design methods, techniques and tools exist for such systems. Individual (mechanical, electrical, network or software) engineering disciplines only offer partial solutions. Multi-paradigm Modeling (MPM) proposes to model every part and aspect of a system explicitly, at the most appropriate level(s) of abstraction, using the most appropriate modelling formalism(s).</description></item><item><title>Inria Associate Teams **ALE**: Agile Language Engineering</title><link>http://example.org/projects/inria-ale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/inria-ale/</guid><description>Software engineering faces new challenges with the advent of modern software-intensive systems such as complex critical embedded systems, cyber-physical systems and the Internet of things. Application domains range from robotics, transportation systems, defense to home automation, smart cities, and energy management, among others. Software is more and more pervasive, integrated into large and distributed systems, and dynamically adaptable in response to a complex and open environment. As a major consequence, the engineering of such systems involves multiple stakeholders, each with some form of domain-specific knowledge, and with an increasingly use of software as an integration layer.</description></item><item><title>Keolis PhD grant</title><link>http://example.org/projects/keolis-phd-grant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/keolis-phd-grant/</guid><description>In this project with the Keolis company we investigate the design of smart city transport simulators that combine top-down modeling and IA techniques. In this context, Jean-Marc Jézéquel acts as Ph.D advisor for Gauthier Lyan with David Gross-Amblard.</description></item><item><title>OkWind PhD grant</title><link>http://example.org/projects/okwind-phd-grant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/okwind-phd-grant/</guid><description>In this project with the OKWind company we investigate the design of solutions in favor of self-consumption for small industries or city districts. In this context, Olivier Barais acts as Ph.D advisor for Alexandre Rio with Yoann Maurel.</description></item><item><title>One Shot Software (OSS)</title><link>http://example.org/projects/one-shot-software/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/one-shot-software/</guid><description>The OSS project investigates an extreme version of moving target defense where a slightly different version of the application is deployed each time it is used (e.g., for crypto functions or payment services). We investigate the analysis, synthesis and transformation techniques to support diversification at 5 points of a software construction pipeline, which, once combined yield up to billions of variants. We also evaluate the support of diversification as a first class property in DevOps.</description></item><item><title>Orange PhD grant</title><link>http://example.org/projects/orange-phd-grant/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/orange-phd-grant/</guid><description>In this project with the Orange company we investigate the security of user interfaces. In this context, Olivier Barais acts as Ph.D advisor for Youssou Ndaye with Arnaud Blouin.</description></item><item><title>PROFILE (Cominlabs)</title><link>http://example.org/projects/profile/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/profile/</guid><description>The PROFILE project brings together experts from law, computer science and sociology to address the challenges raised by online profiling, following a multidisciplinary approach. More precisely, the project will pursue two complementary and mutually informed lines of research: (i) Investigate, design, and introduce a new right of opposition into the legal framework of data protection to better regulate profiling and to modify the behavior of commercial companies towards being more respectful of the privacy of their users; (ii)S Provide users with the technical means they need to detect stealthy profiling techniques as well as to control the extent of the digital traces they routinely produce.</description></item><item><title>VaryVary ANR JCJC</title><link>http://example.org/projects/varyvary/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/projects/varyvary/</guid><description>Most modern software systems (operating systems like Linux, Web browsers like Firefox or Chrome, video encoders like x264 or ffmpeg, servers, mobile applications, etc.) are subject to variation or come in many variants. Hundreds of configuration options, features, or plugins can be combined, each potentially with distinct functionality and effects on execution time, memory footprint, etc. Among configurations, some of them are chosen and do not compile, crash at runtime, do not pass a test suite, or do not reach a certain performance quality (e.</description></item></channel></rss>