<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open positions on Inria/Irisa DiverSE Team</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/</link><description>Recent content in Open positions on Inria/Irisa DiverSE Team</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>(PhD position) Software engineering and virtual reality: towards better development of VR applications</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd-sevr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd-sevr/</guid><description>PhD Position &amp;ldquo;Software engineering and virtual reality: towards better development of VR applications&amp;rdquo; Topic Despite the growing industrial interest in virtual reality (VR) applications, their development is still carried out in an artisanal manner, leading to high development costs. This is particularly the case for families of VR applications (e.g. vehicle maintenance training with learning) for which engineers develop each of the applications in the same family in an ad-hoc manner despite the many commonalities from a software engineering (SE) perspective.</description></item><item><title>A Platform for Multi-Physics Systems Modeling and Simulation</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/idearchitecture/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/idearchitecture/</guid><description>IDE architecture to support multimodal and collaborative modeling and simulation.</description></item><item><title>A top down co-evolution in modern model-based software generation</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-model-code-coevo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-model-code-coevo/</guid><description>Research internship (in Rennes but can also be conducted virtually as well). More details and content can be given below in the PDF.</description></item><item><title>Compiling and Booting Linux Kernel Configurations</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/tuxml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/tuxml/</guid><description>The Linux operating system is one the most complex software ever developed and is crucial to our daily lives. The Linux kernel provides more than 15000 options and perhaps more than 10^6000 possible configurations. Among those configurations, we can wonder whether all of them compile and boot. We have developed TuxML an OSS tool based on Docker/Python to massively gather data about thousands of kernel configurations (see https://github.com/TuxML). We have automatically compiled 200K+ configurations.</description></item><item><title>Conception d'un meta-modèle (ontologie) d'architectures cryptographiques pour la vérification du respect des bonnes pratiques</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/idm4ac/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/idm4ac/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Development of the physical twin of a Fischertechnik-based factory</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-ft-factory-twin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-ft-factory-twin/</guid><description>Le but du stage est d&amp;rsquo;améliorer et d'étendre l&amp;rsquo;implementation d&amp;rsquo;une usine Fischertechnik dans l&amp;rsquo;objectif de l&amp;rsquo;utiliser dans le cadre de travaux autour des jumeaux numériques.</description></item><item><title>DevOps et IHM pour l'ingénierie des systèmes complexes</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/devops-ingsys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/devops-ingsys/</guid><description>DevOps, langages dédiés, environnement de développement, interaction humain-machine, ingénierie dirigée par les modèles, live programming, utilisabilité</description></item><item><title>Domain-Specific Debugging Application to High Performance Computing</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phdcea/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phdcea/</guid><description>co-advised with CEA/DAM, Rennes or Paris</description></item><item><title>DSML for design, orchestration and adaptation of microservices</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshipdsml4microservices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshipdsml4microservices/</guid><description>More details and content can be found below.</description></item><item><title>Développement d'un outil pour l'étude de l'apparition de failles de sécurité dans du code Java</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshiphyperastsecu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshiphyperastsecu/</guid><description>Le but du stage est d'étendre notre outil HyperAST, qui capture l&amp;rsquo;historique Git d&amp;rsquo;un logiciel Java, pour étudier comment les failles de sécurité apparaissent dans le code.</description></item><item><title>Engineering Domain-Specific Languages with Large Language Model-based Assistant</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/dsl-withai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/dsl-withai/</guid><description>(note: this subject can well turn into a PhD thesis)
A domain-specific language (DSL) is a programming language that is tailored to a specific problem domain, rather than being a general-purpose language that can be used for a wide variety of purposes. DSLs are important because they allow developers to express solutions to problems in a way that is natural and intuitive for the domain they are working in, which can make it easier to write and maintain complex systems.</description></item><item><title>Generating a DSL from OpenAPI descriptors for non-developers testers</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshipdslfromopenapi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshipdslfromopenapi/</guid><description>More details and content can be found below.</description></item><item><title>Generative AI (LLMs) for Detecting Abnormal Behavior Through Execution Trace Analysis</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-llm-secu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-llm-secu/</guid><description>This project aims to study the contributions of Generative Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Large Language Models (LLMs) to certain aspects of defensive computer security.</description></item><item><title>Handling Evolution for Polyglot and Live Programming</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd-polylive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd-polylive/</guid><description>Evolution, co-evolution, Polyglot, Live, Programming</description></item><item><title>IA Génératives (LLMs) pour Détecter des Comportements Anormaux par Analyse de Traces d'Exécution</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-llm-secu-fr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-llm-secu-fr/</guid><description>Ce projet vise à étudier les apports des Intelligences Artificielles (IA) génératives et des Grands Modèles de Langues (LLMs) pour certains aspects de la lutte informatique défensive</description></item><item><title>Implementation, visualisation et démonstration d'algorithmes d'undo/redo</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshipundo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshipundo/</guid><description>Implémenter d&amp;rsquo;autres algorithmes et d&amp;rsquo;en faire la démonstration au travers d&amp;rsquo;applications Web.</description></item><item><title>Ingénieur.e Génie Logiciel : Envie de contribuer à la prochaine génération d'IA générative dédiée code et à un avenir éthique ?</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/2025-01-09_engineer_codecommons/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/2025-01-09_engineer_codecommons/</guid><description>Mots clefs : Génie Logiciel, Ingénieurie des languages, Analyses de code, Modélisation, IA éthique, LLM, Cybersécurité, Big Data, Open-source
Rejoignez le projet CodeCommons mené par l'équipe DiverSE à l&amp;rsquo;Inria Rennes, une équipe jeune, dynamique et reconnue mondialement pour son expertise en Génie Logiciel (ingénierie des langages, variabilité logicielle, test automatique, architecture, manipulation de modèle, etc).
Vous travaillerez sur des sujets innovants en collaboration avec des chercheurs : extraction automatique de données, des analyses automatiques de code (caractérisation, qualité, traçabilité, reproductibilité, similarité, etc).</description></item><item><title>Investigating co-evolution in modern polyglot software applications</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-polyglot-coevo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internship-polyglot-coevo/</guid><description>Research internship (in Rennes but can also be conducted virtually as well). More details and content can be given below in the PDF.</description></item><item><title>Large scale code history analysis for improving software stability</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/hyperast-sec/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/hyperast-sec/</guid><description>code analysis, software code history, large scale analysis, software security, empirical study</description></item><item><title>Next generation of development environments</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/ide-next/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/ide-next/</guid><description>domain-specific language, language workbench, IDE, human-computer interaction, DevOps, solution space exploration, user interface</description></item><item><title>PhD (M/F) in computer science: vulnerabilities in code generated by LLMs (TAP project)</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/2024-1212_position_phd_vulnerabilities_in_code_generated_by_llms_tap_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/2024-1212_position_phd_vulnerabilities_in_code_generated_by_llms_tap_project/</guid><description>PhD topic description For the last 60 to 70 years, programming has largely prevailed in the field of computer science, encompassing the capture of intentions and the production of code. Formal specifications have gained in importance thanks to advances in systems modelling and design, enabling more precise capture of objectives. Despite these advances, software engineers are reluctant to write formal specifications, resulting in the absence of a formal statement of intent for large software systems, making debugging and error correction difficult.</description></item><item><title>PhD position "Adaptive Security Framework for Microservices-based Cloud Applications"</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd-security-microservices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd-security-microservices/</guid><description/></item><item><title>PhD position "Applying countermeasures to vulnerabilities in code, through AI-driven refactoring and co-evolution"</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd_refactoring_vulnerabilities_ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd_refactoring_vulnerabilities_ai/</guid><description>PhD with AID (Defense Innovation Agency). Cybersecurity, vulnerabilities, CVEs, AI, refactoring, counter-measures, fixing, Software Heritage, SWH-Sec, Cyber Campus</description></item><item><title>PhD Position "End-user Programming and Large Language Model"</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/enduser-llm/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/enduser-llm/</guid><description>PhD Position &amp;ldquo;End-user Programming and Large Language Model&amp;rdquo; (note: it is also possible to apply for an internship!)
Is it possible to program non-trivial applications and customize code without knowing much about programming? Impressive showcases of Large Language Models (LLMs) like ChatGPT suggest a positive answer [1]. Some people have even claimed that programmers will be replaced or disappear [2]. So, can end-users create working and non-trivial applications, like games, just using instructions in natural language with ChatGPT?</description></item><item><title>PhD position "Modeling, classification, and detection of vulnerabilities and their variants in software code bases using AI"</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd_modeling_vulnerabilities_ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd_modeling_vulnerabilities_ai/</guid><description>PhD with AID (Defense Innovation Agency). Cybersecurity, vulnerabilities, CVEs, AI, modeling, detection, Software Heritage, SWH-Sec, Cyber Campus</description></item><item><title>PhD Position "Uncertainty Management in Software Product Lines" in collaboration with Airbus</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd-variability-uncertainty-oneway/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/phd-variability-uncertainty-oneway/</guid><description>PhD Position &amp;ldquo;Uncertainty Management in Software Product Lines&amp;rdquo; in collaboration with Airbus Topic A software product line is a set of software-intensive systems that share a common, managed set of features satisfying the specific needs of a particular market segment or mission and that are developed from a common set of core assets in a prescribed way. Variability management is a core concern in software product lines, making it possible to select the right set of features to answer a well defined need.</description></item><item><title>Post-Doctoral researcher (F/M) position: vulnerabilities in code generated by LLMs (TAP project)</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/2024-1212_position_post-doctoral_researcher_m_f_vulnerabilities_in_code_generated_by_llms_tap_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/2024-1212_position_post-doctoral_researcher_m_f_vulnerabilities_in_code_generated_by_llms_tap_project/</guid><description>Scientific and Technical Context The TAP Project (Trustworthy Automatic Programming) TAP is a joint project between CNRS-IPAL-IRISA and NUS (National University of Singapore), funded by the DGA and its Singaporean counterpart.
Over the last 60 to 70 years, programming has dominated computer science, involving the capture of intentions and code production. Formal specifications have gained prominence thanks to advances in system modeling and design, allowing for more precise goal capture. Despite these advancements, software engineers are often reluctant to write formal specifications.</description></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Position "A programming model for simulation processes" at CEA DAM (France)</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/postdoc-simulation-ceadam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/postdoc-simulation-ceadam/</guid><description>Postdoctoral Position at CEA DAM (France) &amp;ldquo;A programming model for simulation processes&amp;rdquo; Context Scientific software is often designed in the form of a process including data preprocessing, simulation code, and data postprocessing. In the current state of the practices, this process is either split in several modules put together in an explicit data-flow process, or tightly coupled in a single program. The data-flow processes tend to treat in a very decoupled way the processing of the data from the simulation, most often thanks to persistent data exchanges.</description></item><item><title>Postdoctoral Position CONFVERT: Green Software Configurations</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/confvert-postdoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/confvert-postdoc/</guid><description>Postdoctoral Position &amp;ldquo;CONFVERT: Green Software Configurations&amp;rdquo; The postdoctoral candidate must have spent at least 18 months abroad (outside France) between May 1, 2021, and the project start.
Availability: ready to start 02 January 2026 — application submitted now.
Scientific and Technical Context Modern software is highly configurable; interactions between options and their execution environments (hardware, OS, versions, inputs, build/test pipelines) strongly affect both energy use and performance. CONFVERT targets “green” configurations-settings that minimize energy while preserving acceptable performance—by explicitly modeling and learning from this deep variability, with open data, open tools, and reproducible methods on widely used open‑source stacks.</description></item><item><title>Proposing a DSL for the generation of code, tests and OpenAPI descriptor</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshipdsl4openapi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/internshipdsl4openapi/</guid><description>More details and content can be found below.</description></item><item><title>Replicating Science in the Context of Machine Learning and Software</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/replicatingml/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/replicatingml/</guid><description>One of the best way to understand and contribute to science is to replicate existing studies. For instance, a new algorithm can be proposed in a scientific paper, showing impressive improvements with regards to the state of the art; we can wonder whether the claimed properties really hold, especially in another context.
The aim of this internship is to consider/read specific papers, investigate whether the results can be fully reproduced, and then make vary the experimental conditions (e.</description></item><item><title>Smart Microservicization, Deployment and Dynamic Reconfiguration of Distributed Systems</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/devops-5g/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/devops-5g/</guid><description>an holistic appraoch that assist, or even automate, the microservicization, deployment and dynamic reconfiguration of distributed systems.</description></item><item><title>Software Design and Development Engineer (M/F): vulnerabilities in code generated by LLMs (TAP project)</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/2024-1212_position_software_design_and_development_engineer_m_f_tap_project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/2024-1212_position_software_design_and_development_engineer_m_f_tap_project/</guid><description>Scientific and Technical Context The TAP Project (Trustworthy Automatic Programming) TAP is a joint project between CNRS-IPAL-IRISA and NUS (National University of Singapore), funded by the DGA and its Singaporean counterpart.
Over the last 60 to 70 years, programming has dominated computer science, involving the capture of intentions and code production. Formal specifications have gained prominence thanks to advances in system modeling and design, allowing for more precise goal capture. Despite these advancements, software engineers are often reluctant to write formal specifications.</description></item><item><title>Web front-end testing: large scale analysis and techniques improvement</title><link>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/front-end-analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://www.diverse-team.fr/positions/front-end-analysis/</guid><description>Web front-end, software testing, code analysis, software code history, empirical study, software security, test generation, test amplification, UI coverage</description></item></channel></rss>